<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Ryan Peterman</title>
        <link>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Ryan Peterman</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Making Instagram Video Ads Performant</title>
            <link>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/2021/11/making-instagram-video-ads-performant/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/2021/11/making-instagram-video-ads-performant/</guid>
            <description>Had a lot of fun partnering with the ads org on optimizing the performance of video ads, which had been neglected for some time. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in reading about how we reduced memory errors 98% and drove a 3.9% increase in watch time, check out the blog post here.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Had a lot of fun partnering with the ads org on optimizing the performance of video ads, which had been neglected for some time. If you&rsquo;re interested in reading about how we reduced memory errors 98% and drove a 3.9% increase in watch time, <a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/engineering/making-instagram-video-ads-performant">check out the blog post here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Cutting Threads&#39; Send Latency in Half</title>
            <link>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/2021/03/cutting-threads-send-latency-in-half/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/2021/03/cutting-threads-send-latency-in-half/</guid>
            <description>I did some technical writing at work. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in reading about some of the work my team did check out the post here</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did some technical writing at work. If you&rsquo;re interested in reading about some of the work my team did <a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/engineering/cutting-threads-send-latency-in-half">check out the post here</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Why Write</title>
            <link>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/2021/02/why-write/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/2021/02/why-write/</guid>
            <description>I’ve been thinking about writing for a while but have had difficulty seeing the benefit. Usually when people talk about writing, the benefits I often hear are (1) to connect with others and (2) to build a following. Both of these points may have value but the payoff is uncertain and not completely in my control. To warrant writing, I needed to find other benefits which were in my control and likely to happen.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been thinking about writing for a while but have had difficulty seeing the benefit. Usually when people talk about writing, the benefits I often hear are (1) to <a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/808830209684307968">connect with others</a> and (2) to build a following. Both of these points may have value but the payoff is uncertain and not completely in my control. To warrant writing, I needed to find other benefits which were in my control and likely to happen. With this in mind, I found a few payoffs that satisfy these criteria.</p>
<h3 id="persisting-ideas">Persisting ideas</h3>
<p><a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/319/5865/966.full">Active recall is the most effective way to persist information</a> into your memory. Writing forces you to actively recall information to write it down. My past experience corroborates this. A few years ago I wrote <a href="https://instagram-engineering.com/video-upload-latency-improvements-at-instagram-bcf4b4c5520a">this technical blog post</a> for work. I spent a lot of time getting the details right. This forced me to read into my team’s infrastructure and actively recall that information.</p>
<h3 id="generating-ideas">Generating ideas</h3>
<p>Aside from persisting information, <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/writing44.html">writing also helps me generate more ideas</a>. When I create a rough draft, I start with a thesis, then back up my claims through research and thinking deeply. This creative process helps me think of new ideas.</p>
<h3 id="reducing-mistakes-in-judgement">Reducing mistakes in judgement</h3>
<p>In <em>Thinking Fast and Slow</em>, Dr Kahneman shows through his Nobel prize winning research that most decisions people make come from your subconscious mind. Your subconscious mind is prone to making mistakes in judgement due to logical fallacies and cognitive biases. Writing <a href="https://boz.com/articles/writing-thinking">forces you to articulate your thoughts</a> and bring them into your conscious mind’s focus. Doing this will improve your judgement by avoiding the mistakes of your subconscious mind.</p>
<h3 id="learning-to-write">Learning to write</h3>
<p>As your career progresses, the skills needed to deliver the most impact will change. Early in your career, you will likely need to complete work by your own hand while you build the fundamentals. In most cases, doing things yourself can only go so far though. One way to have more impact is to develop the ability to influence others to ship what matters. With less time you’ll be able to get more done and have more impact. Writing is a scalable way of influencing others.</p>
<p>These payoffs are all in my control and guaranteed to happen. Therefore, it&rsquo;s valueable to write even if only for my own benefit.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Video Processing Latency Improvements</title>
            <link>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/2020/01/video-processing-latency-improvements/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://www.ryanlpeterman.dev/posts/2020/01/video-processing-latency-improvements/</guid>
            <description>I did some technical writing at work. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in reading about some of the work my team does check out the post here</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did some technical writing at work. If you&rsquo;re interested in reading about some of the work my team does <a href="https://instagram-engineering.com/video-upload-latency-improvements-at-instagram-bcf4b4c5520a">check out the post here</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
